Whyte, William Foote Additional Papers /4163
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
William Foote Whyte Additional Papers
1919-2000
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Whyte, William Foote, 1914-2000
/4163
7 cubic feet
7 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
8017032
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
A. Holland-Loucks, June 17, 2011
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 03, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4149 AV: "ASA Award Presentation to William Foote Whyte by Jacqueline Scheier" Audio-Visual Materials /4149: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4168: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4173: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4087: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4094: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4102: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4151: William Foote Whyte Additional Papers /4058: William Foote Whyte Office Records
Whyte, William Foote, 1914-2000; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
8017032
- Testimonial dinner on the Retirement of Angelo Ralph Orlandella, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bill Whyte, 1970-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Orlandella (Angelo Ralph Orlandella), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Some of the Intimate Details Involved in Obtaining the Park Fence, 1940-1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Orlandella, Angelo R. Misc., 1959-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letters to Bill Whyte, from Angelo Ralph Orlandella, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Climate of Conditions in 1919 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 92 North Margin Street, 1934-1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letters to William Foote Whyte, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- William Foote Whyte Misc. Documents, 1969-1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Letters '41-'42, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Lynd Award Guidelines, 1981-1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- American Anthropologist Excerpts; W. Whyte, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- The Use of Field Study in Undergraduate Education, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- For Correspondence, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- 1940's Personnal and Professional Correspondence, 1943-1948 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Personnal Correspondence, 1948-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Pecci, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Bronxville Schools Bulletin, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- (HAP) Human Affairs Program, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- New York Times, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Interview W. Whyte, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Other Correspondence, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- CRA, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Scope and Contents
  One Photograph
- Bulletin; The Society for Social Research, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- On the Manipulation of Men, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Public Policy, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Del Prado, Nunez, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- STA (Social Thoery for Action) Book Reviews, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Toward an Alternate Economic Policy, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Social Theory and Methods, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Human Organizations, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Misc. Publications, 1945-1982 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Writings on Education, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Strategies for Organizational and Community Development, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Union Management Relations, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Cornell's Industrial Innovation Service (CIIS), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Research Reports for the Creole Petroleum Organization #1, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Research Reports for the Creole Petroleum Corporation #2, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Aluminum Company of Canada, Limited (Management Problems of the Mechanical Divison), 1958 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- W. Whyte, Theory, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Peru Planning Notes, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Peru Notes 1960-1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- On the Politics of Social Research in Peru, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Peru Letters 1968-1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Libro de Codigo Maestro, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Politics in Peru, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- 1950's Letters, 1953-1955 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Proposed film "Street Corner Society", 1988 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Covert Ops., 1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Henry Reuss Congress, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Peru 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Cold Spring Institute, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Peru Letters 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Planification of the Social Changes and the Peruvian Process, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Spanish; English
- Peru-Latin America, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Peru 1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Peru Notes 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Misc. Documents (WFW), 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Potato Research (Peru), 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Field Notes Rural Development, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Ideas (WFW), 1973-1994 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- T.U. Lankide (Trabajo Y Union), 1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Spanish
- T.U. Lankide (Trabajo y Union) 1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- T.U. Lankide (Trabajo Y Union)1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Tiempos de Esperanza, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- T.U. Lankide (Trabajo y Union) 1994, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- 1987 Txostena Memoria 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Grupo Cooperativo Mondragon, Consejo General, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Fagor Annual Reports, 1986-1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- T.U. Lankide (Trabajo Y Union) 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- T.U. Lankide (Trabajo Y Union), 1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- People in Petroleum, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- People in Petroleum copy #2, 1943-1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Annual Reports 1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  English, Spanish
- T.U. Lankide (Trabajo Y Union) 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- T.U. Lankide (Trabajo Y Union) 1994 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- T.U. Lankide (Trabajo Y Union) 1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- The Tremont Hotel Study 1945-1946 An Operational Report (Box 5, Folder 7)
- PEWS ILR Excerpt, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Public Policy, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Human Relations 1944-1948, 1944-1982 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- PEWS Financing, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Charlotte Summer School, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Personnal Letters, Notes (WFW), 1936-1990 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Personnal Publicity, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Potential Law Suit, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- STA Review, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- SCS South America, 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- People in Petroleum copy #3, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- From Conflict to Cooperation; A Study in Union-Management Relations, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Modern Methods in Social Research, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- WFW Reprints, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Methods and Theories, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Worker Ownership and Control, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- North End Studies, 1939-1943 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Policy and Politics Academic + National, 1969-1987 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Peru and Culture Studies, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- WFW Letters 1995 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Floppy Disk 3.5 inches
- WFW Theories and Ideas, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Files for Hand Drive, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Floppy Disk 3.5 inches "File's from Pop's Computer"
- Social Entrepreneurs Social System changes, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Floppy Disk 3.5 inches "Social Entrepreneurs + Social System Changes"
- Skyriver Peru Participation South, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- John W. McConnell, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Floppy Disk 3.5 inches "McConnell"
- Bethesda Soc-Think, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Floppy Disk 3.5 inches "Bethesda Soc-Think"
- Autobiography of William Foote Whyte, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Floppy Disk 3.5 inches "Auto cord Practice Ordanel Why BK"
- Ideas - Mondragon, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Floppy Disk 3.5 inches "Mondragon"
- Social Theory for Action - Manuscript, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Floppy Disk 3.5 inches "STA"
- Writings by William Foote Whyte Folder #1, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Writings by William Foote Whyte Folder #2, 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Writings by William Foote Whyte Folder #3, 1988-1990 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Street Corner Society (Chinese Version), 1943 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Chinese
- Floppy Disk Case, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Floppy Disk 3.5 inches "Sctalk 5oth Annual" Floppy Disk 3.5 inches "Shriver Peru Participation South" Floppy Disk 3.5 inches "Farms Lux X-mas Ny State Kennedy, Fran. Cornell" Floppy Disk 3.5 inches, Marked "won't read"
- Bibliographies Folder #1, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Bibliographies Folder #2, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Projects, 1943-1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- The 1980's Buyouts, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Coping with the New Manufacturing Organization, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Various Writings by WFW, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Social Theory in Action, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Auto Cord and Reference, 1931-1990 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Preface to the Japanese Edition - Mondragon, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- New Manufacturing Organization (NMO), 1989 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Ralph Orlandella Response to Boelan, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Penn Paper, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Revisiting SCS and other Works, 1988-1990 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Social Theory, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Social Theory and Research, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Interviews November 19, 1985 - January 14, 1986, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- "The Closing of the Atlus Chain Company" By Robert Pankin, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- "O&O Breakthrough the Philadelphia Story" by William foote Whyte, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 18)